Pyline Tangsuvanich

pylinet.github.io/personalsite/inkedin.com/in/pyline

Profile

Pyline is an architect with +7 years of experience in residential, commercial interiors, and urban design projects. Most recently, she was a Studio Operations Manager for a start-up called Cottage, where she served as a bizops leader for the company. She is an advocate for knowledge sharing and enjoys standing up systems to enable her teammates to be more productive.

Experience

Small Tiger LLC | San Francisco Bay Area

Founder and Freelance Design Consultant from May 2022 to current

- Established a consultancy focused on providing operations, design, and documentation services for small architecture firms and start-ups in the AEC space.
- Currently working with a RE:PRACTICE to lead the construction documentations for a health clinic and consulting with a residential start-up to supercharge their Revit workflow.

Cottage | San Francisco Bay Area

Design Studio Operations Manager from July 2021 to May 2022

- Collaborated cross-functionally to identify opportunities to enhance the experience and reduce bottlenecks for Cottage homeowners, freelance designers, and general contractors.
- Scaled Cottage's designer freelance network by x4 within 9 months to +30 designers by active & passive outreach, tracking applicants via CRM, and vetting +500 applicants.
- Provided mentorship & technical support to the freelancers thorough hands-on training, documentation creation and continuous onboarding to ensure their success at Cottage.
- Executed +10 accessory dwelling units from schematic design through to permit submission in collaboration with Cottage project managers and general contractors.

Hana at CBRE | New York City

Design Manager from January 2021 to May 2021

- Created and managed a 120-page document on Hana brand & physical standards for commercial interior fit-outs across all of our U.S. projects
- Led Revit & BIM operations for the team to ensure consistency across deliverables and to reduce time to create 3D models.
- Managed AoR's and external contractors during the construction documentation & build-out process for (5) locations, totaling approximately +250K SF in space.

Senior Designer from April 2019 to Dec 2020

- Analyzed over 500K SF in commercial real estate property in NA, EMEA, and APAC by producing test fits to present to landlord's and internal stakeholders.
- Collaborated closely with FF&E vendors to standardize our specifications and budgets.

WXY architecture + urban design | New York City

Architectural and Urban Designer from Oct 2016 to Jan 2019

- Contributed to the design and CD process for a 16,000 SF pavilion at the Javits Center by serving as the BIM manager, developing presentations, and coordinating with consultants.
- Served as the lead urban designer for the Brooklyn Navy Yard's 2030 Master plan, which includes +1m SF in potential development and waterfront public space.

SHoP Architects | New York City

Junior Designer from Sept 2014 to Aug 2015

 Participated in a design competition for Uber's HQ in SF. Led the physical model production and contributed to documentation efforts during design development.

Education

Rice University

- Bachelor of Architecture, AIA Henry Adams Medal, '16
- Bachelor of Arts, summa cum laude, '14

Certifications

- Licensed Architect in the State of New York
- · NCARB Certified

Expertise

- · Design Systems & Operations
- Client Engagement & Presentations
- · Project Delivery & Management
- · Real Estate Due Diligence
- Test Fits & Space Planning
- Design Documentation and Drafting
- Knowledge Management, Mentorship and Training
- Consultant & Third Party Management

Tools

- Revit & BIM360
- Rhinoceros & Grasshopper
- AutoCAD & ReCap
- 3D Scanning & Matterport
- Airtable
- · Bluebeam Revu
- Figma
- Adobe Suite
- Javascript, CSS, HTML
- · Git and Github

Recent Features

- Airtable Interface Contest Winner, Sept 2022.
- Interview feature in Rice Magazine for article titled "Think Like an Architect", May 2022
- Webinar speaker for <u>"Women in AEC" hosted by Voyansi,</u>
 Dec. 2020
- Mentor for <u>Rice Architecture</u> <u>School Mentorship Program</u> (RAMP), Oct 2021 to current